[Music]
hi this is Kenny from business Central
if you're using powerbi for sales I have
a great offer for you in version 26.1 we
come with an enhanced powerp app that
makes the great app you have from last
semester even better so uh let's dive in
and see some of the new capabilities so
we changed or we focused on four
different topics or themes in the
powerbi sales app in the version 2025
release way one again remember that this
is coming in
26.1 the first is the sales life the
sales life cycle now if you think about
an item that you sell to a
customer you have different faces you
might not go through all of them in a
sale um you might go to directly to a
sales order and and sell it but you
might also have a quote or even an
opportunity if you use the CR
module but a sale that where customer
returns or you have credit memos is not
like a great sale right because then
you're actually not making the money
that is in the sales order amount
because some of that needs to be
deducted in the last wave the sales app
was focusing on sales orders and sales
invoices and in this wave we kind of
move left and right so both in this more
in the CRM world and also looking at the
quality of the sales in return
analysis Let's uh dive in to the
opportunity so the opportunity overview
report have like many of the reports you
have some key kpis or numbers in the top
here and then you have different aspects
of opportunities for instance the value
by status so here you see one or in
progress or lost opportunities you can
also see the Sal sales cycle whether
opportunities are new existing the The
Funnel of different stages if you name
in this case we don't have a name for
the first description here but we do
have initial and qualification so you
can see the different opportunities by
that and you can even uh see from where
in the world your your opportunities are
if I expand my map here and just make
this a bit uh bigger I can see that
something is going on in Australia
apparently this is where we have our
opportunities and if I hover over this I
can see uh some geographic
representation and also the estimated
value by
location so um so this is the
opportunity report let's move uh on and
look at some uh sales quote
analysis so I'll just pick the sales
quote report here sales quote
overview again you see same pattern some
kpis in the top but now you can you can
dive into sales quotes by customer
including an idea about what profit
would this particular quote actually
give so not only focusing on the sales
amount and like how much we sell but
also what would be profit from from this
quote you can see quotes over time you
can even track your sales staff and I
kind of see Jim is killing it here
compared to uh to others Benjamin not so
much uh so so that gives also like a
holistic view on quotes both by customer
by sales staff and uh what what people
uh is quoting and a time graph for
that and then let's let's look at return
orders so that's return order overview
again here you can see kpis like what is
like wasted like this is minus sales
amount because people are returning
things and this is the missing profit uh
opportunity here because of return
orders you have an idea here about about
which customers return the most of
course you can you can sort this just to
kind of get that to see whether this is
a good or bad customer you can see why
people return things um and you can also
see returns over time so whether
suddenly maybe you have a quality issue
maybe you're overselling I don't know
that's uh that's up to you to find the Y
this is just giving you some numbers and
izations for return order Returns the
next topic is
profitability so um not only how much we
sell and the amount we sell for but also
is it actually making money so let's
dive into sales by
customer and um sales by customer is an
existing report that now got some new
visuals the first here is a Paro
analysis so I can simply say what is the
population of my customers that generate
70% of my profit or if I want to go for
a higher amount uh then I know that
Alpine Rel cloud adum and school for
Fine Art
are accommodating for 90% of my sales
now this data set is very like evenly
distributed you probably have more
variation in the profit by customer so
we also added some new uh measures here
in the details so profit uh profit
margin and then uh a visual on from
where in the world you get your sales
amount by location so now I can see that
in Australia uh we have a certain total
amount but we're also doing some sales
up in Washington state in the
US a different way of looking look at
your profit is not by customer but by
item so uh so here on the sales by item
we have two new visuals to the right the
first one is sales uh by item category
over time this is a way to to to look
for patterns such as seasonality or
maybe certain item categories like get
more interesting sales-wise over time so
that's that's one way of looking at your
your sales not at a point in time but
but over time and the second visual here
is your item profitability a bubble
chart with two axes two measures we we
mapped against each other the sales
quantity on the xaxis and the sales
amount on the y- AIS and then if I hover
over one of these bubbles I can see the
the profit margin and the sales amount
and quantity and so one so depending on
where in this grid my bubbles are um
that have an indication of how
profitable they are here I have 85%
profitability where here I only have 22
so by seeing a cluster of items here I
might be able to see whether my product
portfolio I sell is the right one or the
pricing is right um maybe some items in
my inventory i something that that I
don't need or maybe I sell them in
bundles so that's why I need it but here
I can at at least you get an idea about
profitability for your for your
inventory for the items in your
inventory profitability is also
something where you can look at your
sales staff let's look at sales by
salesperson this is an existing report
that got some new visuals so uh here on
the sales metrics you can see for Joe
sales amount Joe generated also the
profit uh they generated and the margin
they generated you can see an overview
of the opportunities in the CRM module
if you use that by different uh people
in your sales staff and again the same
kind of Bobble chart analysis not by
item but now by salesperson so here Jim
is generating
23% margin with an amount where some
others uh have like generate much more
not only like Revenue but actually
profit so I'm not saying that uh that
you should fire gym I'm just I'm I'm
just saying that this this could be a
way to also have um look at the sales
staff on with some different metrics and
and see whether it's
it's it's profitability
or the sales amount or the quantity of
sale that drive these different sales
staff um the final profitability metric
is on the overview page let me just
navigate to that the sales overview here
this is also just an updated of existing
report but the top five customer and the
sales amount by
salesperson now show kind of the
breakdown on on the amounts so for
instance you can see here there's a zero
here everything to the left is negative
so here you have credit memos um and you
have your return orders and then on the
the right side here are the revenue
generating amounts and the same thing
goes not only for customers but for
salespeople now why would that be
interesting there could be many factors
to these numbers but uh but what if when
whenever Le Ena is selling something
she's overselling so that means there's
a lot of returns or credits going on in
in that sale um so by just
seeing like these different numbers
ordered by sales staff could give you an
indication of maybe there's some
training um maybe there's a different
way to approach customers so that they
don't return so so many of the
items the third top IC in the new powerp
app is demographics in different ways
Let's uh let's take a look if I choose
the sales by location
report this is an existing report that
got a map so now you can see from where
in the world your customers are coming
from and the size of the bubbles
indicate how much you how much revenue
or how much sales amount these different
geographies generate maybe this is even
a report that you want to have kind of
blown up on the wall to have your world
domination sales map I don't know up to
you a different way of looking at
demographics is the new report um sales
demographics so in this report we also
have not the amount but the number of
customers by location in a map and we
also have different metrics sales
metrics by the sales amount and profit
by item category up here by item here
and uh some details by customer posting
group so that's just different ways to
to analyze demographics uh
composition of your sales numbers the
last topic is AI assisted ways to
analyze data now ai can be many things
um it can be generative AI what you're
going to see here is applications of
like very like old and but Prov proven
data mining techniques um that I think
work well in sales and
marketing so on the sales decomposition
report here you can see like a tree
structure or an analysis here that
starts with a sales amount and then I
have expanded this three levels um to
explain the high contributors to sales
now if I choose the next part here I can
either simply choose my own analysis not
AI assisted for instance maybe I want to
see um the location
name for to see kind of where is how is
that distributed and I can then um kind
of go into the city dimension for West
warehouse and see uh see that as well um
so that's one way of looking at using
this that you can choose yourself the
type of analysis you would like um but
you could also have statistics and
statistics model choose for you either
what are the high value contributors or
what are the low value depending on what
you're interested in maybe you want to
see like contributors to to high sales
but it could also mean that you want to
to kind of find out where are the
Troublesome area
so let's just go for for high value here
and the algorithm simply found out that
the the location is the next Dimension
that describes a lot of sales and here
we have the contributors for that uh of
which blank the warehouse with uh well
or the entries with no Warehouse is um
is is the contributing the most and I
can just expand on and on and on here I
can see that Jim is killing it at least
in this part of it so that's the sales
decomposition AI assisted
report the next report is actually two
different reports in one it's called key
sales
influencers and uh in here we also have
a statistical model that um is helping
driving some insights based on a
question and the question here is what
influences the document number to be
sales invoice which means we do a sale
we could also have different others um
like what is a most common for a a
credit memo or return shipment for now
we'll just do do a sales invoice and the
algorithm found some different key
influence influencers for that the the
first two seem to be very related um
that whenever Jim Olive here is involed
evolved you can see that there is a
1.6 times higher likelihood that you
make a sale and then for this particular
Insight you also get a small explanation
here with a graph uh where you can see
the the other let's just pick the
salesperson here you can see on average
the sales staff produce 50 51% but Jim
is leading with 80 for here um to
explain sales so this is sorted by
impact but there you can also sort by
count here would be the number of sales
and in here it's the same insights it
wouldn't have to be depending on your
data you can see for instance for item
sales that there are kind of four items
that are um leading so if the sale is
about a mosow swiveled share in red um
it's
1.53 times more likely to sell than than
other um than the the main po or the
average population so that's the key
influencer
report the other one other report is a
segmentation of the data space around
your sales again we are asking about
things that can explain the sales
invoice and the algorithm segmented or
found four significant segments uh that
we can now explore so let me uh look at
the first one
here so in this segment there are some
properties that describe it the
algorithm can cannot give it a real name
but if we are outside adelade um the
global Dimension is outside medium and
we are selling chairs and especially if
Jim is the salesperson this also
confirms to the analysis that Jim Jim is
really killing it then we get um 30
percentage Point higher sales that on
average um and we can explore this
segment even further with a AI
generated learn more here let's just oh
there was nothing here let's try the the
other segment and see if there's
something yeah so um so there's more to
dive in in segment two with some uh some
autogenerate
reports in a sense that uh that might
explain more um around this segment so
that's the key influencer uh Report with
the key influencers u Way of analyzing
and the segmentation at the to top
segments way of analyzing and all of
this is assisted by Machine learning or
AI so that that wraps up the demos for
the enhanced powerbi app for sales that
we ship in version 26.1 as you can see
we have seven new reports coming you've
seen most of this in these demos and we
have some updated reports I probably
missed a few um so I hope that you will
um upgrade if you're already using the
app and if you're not then I think
you're missing out on a lot of insights
that could help you drive uh your sales
part of your organization
if you want to learn more about this
exciting topic of sales
analytics uh all of this is documented
in our documentation for users and you
find the easiest way to find that is
using this AKA link here so if you open
a browser and type in
aka.ms
slbc sales analytics this will take you
to a landing page and I'll just briefly
show you what you can find there so the
sales analytics part of the
documentation is uh under sales and uh
the overview you get here is both the
overview for the powerbi app you can
investigate all the reports with
screenshots from here you don't have to
install it just to get curious and um
and then there is also guidance on how
to do ad hoc analysis with data analysis
on sales scenarios as well as buildin
sales reports within overview of that so
hopefully this documentation give you
anything you need for the bi triangle
for sales analytics in the top we have
the kpis with powerbi in the middle we
have data analysis with um or ad hog
analysis with with data analysis on list
and queries and uh for the operational
part we have Legacy reports and the new
Excel reports for
sales that all we had for you in this
video hope you have a great launch event
thank you